<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Technical Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://kracekumar.github.io/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Technical Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 11:43:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kracekumar.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Books</title>
      <link>https://kracekumar.github.io/post/155204597600/2016-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 11:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kracekumar.github.io/post/155204597600/2016-books/</guid>
      <description>I was watching one of my favorite Tamil writer S Ramakrishnan’s video about books. Somewhere in the middle of the talk, he suggests the audience to write down the list of books they read this year and share with others. Irrespective of how short or tall the list is, undoubtedly people will pick up from the list someday. I bought the idea and documenting the book list.
English Read  The 5 Elements of Effective Thinking Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking - The book is about introverts, what constittues who they are and their world - My Review The Fire Next Time Jonathan Livingston Seagull Animal Farm - Satire on Russian Revolution - My Review The Metamorphosis Outliers: The Story of Success - the factors that contribute to high levels of success Man’s Search for Meaning - Hope during adversity - My Review How to Stay Sane  Currently reading  The Gifts of Imperfection: Let Go of Who You Think You’re Supposed to Be and Embrace Who You Are Nonviolent Communication: A Language of Life Grokking Algorithms An illustrated guide for programmers and other curious people Mirrors: Stories of Almost Everyone - World historic events in few sentences The Trial Flowers for Algernon  Dropped the ball  Surely You’re Joking, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>